渴望
Longing
生锈
Rusted
十七
Seventeen
黎明
Daybreak
火炉
Furnace
九
Nine
善良
Benign
回祖国
Homecoming
一
One
火车货车车厢
Freight car
早上好  士兵
Good morning, Soldier.
愿意服从
Ready to comply.
我有个任务要交给你
I have a mission for you.
制裁和取回
Sanction and extract.
不留活口
No witnesses.
干得好  士兵
Well done Soldier.
拉各斯
现今
你看见什么了
Alright, what do you see?
普通的片区巡警
Standard beat cops.
小警局
Small station.
警察局
街区安静
Quiet street.
是个不错的目标
It's a good target.
南角有台自动取款机  也就是说
There's an ATM in the south corner, which means...
有摄像头
Cameras.
两条交叉街道都是单行的
Both cross streets are one way.
不算是很好的逃跑路线
So compromised escape routes.
警局被抢
不算是很好的逃跑路线
So compromised escape routes.
警局被抢
也就是说我们的目标不在乎被看到
Means our guy doesn't care about being seen
武器被出售给恐怖分子
也不怕在逃跑时造成混乱
he isn't afraid to make a mess on the way out.
看到半个街区外的那辆逍遥了吗
You see that Range Rover halfway up the block?
看到了  红色那辆吗  还不错
Yeah, the red one. It's cute.
而且是防弹的
It's also bullet proof,
意味着是私人保安
which means private security,
也意味着更多枪
which means more guns,
意味着会让某些人更加头疼  比如我们
which means more headaches for somebody, probably us.
你们知道我能用意念移动物体吧
You guys know I can move things with my mind, right?
小心谨慎必须成为你的本能
Looking over your shoulder needs to become second nature.
有人跟你说过你有点多疑吗
Anybody ever tell you, you're a little paranoid.
没当面说过  怎么  你听到什么了吗
Not to my face. Why, did you hear something?
伙计们  精神集中点
Eyes on target, folks.
这是半年来最可靠的关于朗姆洛的线索了
It's the best lead we've on Rumlow in 6 months.
我可不想跟丢了
I don't want to lose him.
如果他看到我们  那就不是问题了
If he sees us coming that won't be a problem,
他算是恨死我们了
he kind of hates us.
山姆  看到那辆垃圾车了吗
Sam, see that garbage truck?
追踪它
Tag it.
进行X光扫描
Give me X-ray.
重量分析
.
货物重13825公斤
最大载重
轮廓扫描
卡车达到了最大载重  驾驶员有枪
That truck's loaded for max weight, and the driver's armed.
-是辆冲撞车  -行动
- It's a battling ram. - Go now.
怎么了
What?
他的目标不是警察局
He's not hitting the police.
传染性疾病研究所
防弹衣都是AR15
Body armor. AR15s
发现七名敌人
I make 7 hostiles.
还剩五个
I make 5.
山姆
Sam.
四个
4.
朗姆洛在三层
Rumlow's on the third floor.
-旺达  就像练习时那样  -那毒体呢
- Wanda. Just like we practice. - What about the gas?
吸出来
Get it out.
生物危害品
.
装走
Pack it up.
发射
他来了
He's here.
-朗姆洛拿走了生物武器  -我这就去
- Rumlow has a biological weapon. - I'm on it.
我不怕这招了
I don't work like that no more.
手雷来了
Fire in the hole.
不
No!
山姆  他开装甲战车向北走了
Sam. He's in an AFV heading north.
把这个带去机场
Take this to the airstrip.
我们跑不过他  弃车
We're not gonna out run him. Lose the truck.
-你去哪和我们汇合  -我们不汇合
- Where are you going to meet us? - I'm not.
我看到四个  他们分头了
I got 4, they're splitting up.
我负责左边两个
I got the two on the left.
他们把装备扔了
They ditched their gear.
得靠猜了  只有一个人拿走了武器
It's a shell game now. One of them has the payload.
你在这儿呢  你个混蛋
There you are, you son of a bitch.
这一刻我等好久了
I've been waiting for this!
东西不在他这儿
He doesn't have it.
我没找到
I'm empty.
闪开
Out of the way!
放下枪
Drop it.
不然我就把这个扔了
Or I'll drop this.
-放下枪  -他说到做到
- Drop it! - He'll do it!
武器拿到了  谢谢  山姆
Payload secured. Thanks, Sam.
别谢我
Don't thank me.
-我才不要谢那东西  -他叫红翼
- I'm not thanking that thing. - His name is Redwing.
-我还是不会谢它  -他多可爱  摸摸他吧
- I'm still not thanking it. - He's cute. Go ahead, pet him.
来啊
Come on!
这下是为了你拿大楼砸我的脸
This is for dropping a building on my face.
考虑到种种情况  我觉得我看起来还算不错
I think I look pretty good, all things considered.
你的买家是谁
Who's your buyer?
他认得你
You know he knew you.
你那个朋友  好哥们  你的巴基
You pal, your buddy, your Bucky.
-你说什么  -他记得你
- What did you say? - He remembered you.
我当时在场  他还泪汪汪的
I was there. He got all weepy about it.
然后他们就又把他的脑子搅乱了
Till they put put his brain back in the blender.
他想告诉你句话
He wanted you to know something.
他对我说
He said to me,
"请转告罗杰斯"
"Please tell Rogers,"
"该走的时候  就得走"
"When you gotta go, you gotta go."
你得随我一起来
And you're coming with me.
天哪
Oh my...
山姆  我们需要
Sam. We need...
消防救援  在大楼南面
Fire and rescue, on the south side of the building.
我们得马上上去
We got to get up here.
尽量记住九月的美好
Try to remember the kind of September
那时草地仍碧绿
When grass was green...
醒醒  孩子  跟你父亲告别
Wake up, dear. Say goodbye to your father.
沙发上的流浪汉是谁
Who's the homeless person on the couch?
这就是我爱回家过圣诞的原因
This is why I love coming home for Christmas.
因为你们就要走了
Right before you leave town.
好好说话  亲爱的
Be nice, dear.
他出国留学好容易回来一次
He's been studying abroad.
真的吗  学的哪个姑娘  她叫什么
Really, which broad? What's her name?
坎迪斯
Candice.
拜托你  周一之前别把房子烧了
Do me a favour. Try not to burn the house down before Monday.
好  那就周一再烧
Okay, so it's Monday.
知道了  我会据此安排我长袍派对的时间
That is good to know. I will plan my Toga party accordingly.
你们要去哪
Where're you going?
你父亲要带我去巴哈马群岛渡个假
Your father's flying us to the Bahamas for a little get away.
也许得先去一趟别处
We might have to make a quick stop.
去五角大楼吗
At the Pentagon. Right?
别担心
Don't worry.
你肯定会喜欢那里餐厅的节日菜单
You're gonna love the holiday menu at the commissary.
据说讽刺是衡量一个人潜力的标准
You know, they say sarcasm is a metric for potential.
如果真是这样  你以后一定能成为一个伟人
If that's true, you'll be a great man some day.
我去拿包
I'll get the bags.
你不在的时候他非常想念你
He does miss you when you are not here.
老实说  你也会想我们的
And frankly, you're going to miss us.
因为这是我们最后一次在一起
Because this is the last time we're all going to be together.
你知道后来发生了什么
You know what's about to happen.
说点什么吧  不说你会后悔的
Say something. If you don't, you'll regret it.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我知道你尽力了
And I knew you did the best you could.
我希望事情是这样的
That's how I wished it happened.
二元扩张倒退框架  简称"二扩"
Binarily Augmented Retro-Framing... or "BARF".
天哪  这缩写还得好好想想
God, I got to work on that acronym.
一种极其昂贵的通过控制海马体
An extremely costly method, of hijacking the hippocampus
清除创伤记忆的手段
to clear... traumatic memories.
这无法改变
It doesn't change the fact
他们根本没能到达机场的事实
that they never made it to the airport,
或是我为了逃避悲伤所做的那些事  但是
or the things I did to avoid processing my grief. But...
再者  我这个治疗实验花费了6.11亿美元
Plus, 611 million dollars for my little therapeutic experiment.
任何一个正常人都不会赞助这个项目
No one in their right mind would ever funded it.
提醒我一下  麻省理工的宗旨是什么
Help me out. What's the MIT mission statement.
创造  传播和保护知识
To generate, disseminate and preserve knowledge,
与他人协作
and work with others,
尽全力去挑战世界的极限
to bring to bear on the world's great challenges.
你们  就是他人
Well, you, are the others.
尽管没有大肆宣传  你们所面临的挑战
And quiet as it's kept the challenges facing you
也是人类所遭遇的严峻的
are the greatest mankind has ever known.
另外  你们大多数都破产了
Plus, most of you are broke.
或者说  你们之前是
Also, rather you were.
即刻生效  在座各位都将得到
As of this moment, every student has been made an equal recipient
九月基金的拨款
of the inaugural September Foundation Grant.
就是说  你们所有人的项目都得到批准资助了
As in, all of your projects have just been approved and funded.
没有附加条款  不收税
No strings. No taxes.
放手去  改变未来吧
Just... reframe the future.
从现在开始
Starting now.
现在我要请出基金负责人  派珀·波茨
别怕犯错  放手做吧
Go break some eggs.
我简直  真是要窒息了
That uh... That took my breathe away.
托尼  太慷慨了  那么多钱
Tony, so generous, so much money.
我出于好奇问一句
I... Out of curiosity and...
拨款会有一部分给教职工吗
Will any portion of that grant be made available to faculty?
我知道  真没品  但听我说
I know, ew, gross, but hear me out.
我有个关于自熟热狗的绝妙点子
I have got this killer idea for a self cooking hotdog.
基本上就是嵌入化学引燃剂
Basically, chemical detonator embedded...
洗手间在这边吗
Restroom's this way, yeah?
是的  嵌在肉架中
Yeah. Embedding in the meat shaft.
斯塔克先生  提词器的事很抱歉
Mr. Stark, I am so sorry about the telepromter.
我不知道波茨女士不来了
I didn't know Miss Potts has canceled.
他们没来得及改
They didn't have time to fix it.
这
It's...
没事  我马上回来
fine. I..I..I'll be right back.
我们等下再聊
We'll catch up later.
你为那些年轻人做的事真是不错
That was nice, what you did for those young people.
他们应得的
Oh, they deserve it.
也让我的良心好过些
Plus it helps ease my conscious.
据说慷慨与内疚是有关联的
They say, there's a correlation between generosity and guilt.
但你有的是钱
But, you got the money.
可以尽情犯错
Break as many eggs as you like.
对吧
Right?
你要上去吗
Are you going up?
我就想待在这里
I'm right where I want to be.
行了  别动
Okay, okay.
对不起  职业病
Sorry, it's an occupational hazard.
我在国务院工作  人力资源部
I work for the State department. Human resources.
我知道这很无聊
I know it's boring.
但这让我能养活我的儿子
But, it enabled me to raise a son.
我很为他的成长骄傲
I'm very proud of what he grew up to be.
他叫查理·斯宾塞
His name was Charlie Spencer.
你杀了他
Your murdered him.
在索科威亚
In Sokovia.
当然  这对你来说毫不重要
Not that that matters in the least to you.
你以为你为我们而战
You think you fight for us?
其实你只是为自己
You just fight for yourself.
谁会为我儿子复仇  斯塔克
Who's going to avenge my son, Stark?
他死了  都怪你
He's dead. And I blame you.
上月  在尼日利亚拉各斯  11名瓦坎达公民
11 Wakandans were among those killed during a confrontation
在复仇者联盟与雇佣兵的冲突中
between the Avengers and a group of mercenaries
起诉复仇者联盟  全球反暴力
在复仇者联盟与雇佣兵的冲突中
between the Avengers and a group of mercenaries
起诉复仇者联盟  全球反暴力
不幸遇难
in Lagos, Nigeria, last month.
起诉复仇者联盟  全球反暴力
这些通常与世隔绝的瓦坎达人
The traditionally reclusive Wakandans
瓦坎达
这些通常与世隔绝的瓦坎达人
The traditionally reclusive Wakandans
在袭击发生时  正在拉各斯进行公益服务
were on an outreach mission in Lagos when the attack occurred.
瓦坎达国王特查卡要求问责复仇者联盟
我国人民的鲜血洒在了外国领土上
Our people's blood is spilled on foreign soil.
不仅是因为犯罪行为
Not only because of the actions of criminals,
还因为阻止犯罪的人的冷漠
but by the indifference of those pledge to stop them.
牺牲无辜者取得的胜利  根本算不上胜利
Victory at the expense of the innocent, is no victory at all.
瓦坎达国王接着...
The Wakanda King went on to...
他们不受国际法的限制
They are operating outside and above the international law.
如果我们不回应此类行为  就会变成这样
Because that's the reality, if we don't respond to acts like these.
旺达·马克西莫夫这样的能力增强者
What legal authority does an enhanced individual
有什么法律权利在尼日利亚行动
like Wanda Maximoff have to operate in Nige...
-都怪我  -不是的
- It's my fault. - That's not true.
那就把电视再打开  他们可指名道姓了
Then turn the TV back on, they're being very specific.
我早该拆除那件炸弹背心
I should've clocked that bomb vest
而不是让你不得不动手
long before you have to deal with it.
朗姆洛提到"巴基"
Rumlow said 'Bucky' and...
突然间  我又成了那个布鲁克林的16岁少年
All of a sudden, I was a 16 year old kid again in Brooklyn.
有人死了
And people died.
-这怪我  -怪我们俩
- It's on me. - It's on both of us.
这份工作
This job...
我们尽可能救下更多的人
We try to save as many people as we can.
有时并不能救每个人
Sometimes that doesn't mean everybody,
但如果我们无法接受这一点
but, if we can't find a way to live with that,
下次
then next time...
也许我们谁都救不了
maybe nobody get saved.
小幻  我们谈过的
Vis, we talked about this.
是啊  但门开着  所以我以为
Yes. But the door was opened so I assumed that...
罗杰斯队长说斯塔克先生回来让我通知他
Captain Rogers wished to know when Mr. Stark was arriving.
谢谢  我马上下去
Thank you. I'll be right down.
我...走门
I'll... use the door.
还有  他带了位客人
Oh, and apparently, he's brought a guest.
你知道是谁吗
You know who it is?
国务卿
The Secretary of State.
五年前  我心脏病发作
5 years ago, I had a heart attack.
打高尔夫球后挥杆时昏了过去
and dropped right in the middle of my backswing.
结果  那成了我人生最大的幸事
Turned out, it was the best round of my life
因为经历了13小时的手术和三重搭桥术之后
because after 13 hours of surgery and a triple bypass.
我发现了四十年军队生涯没教过我的东西
I found something 40 years in the army never taught me:
远见
perspective.
全世界欠复仇者联盟一个无法偿还的人情
The world owes the Avengers an unpayable debt.
你们为我们而战
You have... fought for us.
保护了我们  拿生命冒险
Protected us. Risked your lives.
虽然有很多人把你们当成英雄
But while a great many people see you as heroes.
但也有一些人
There are some...
更愿意用"义务警员"这个词
who would prefer the word "vigilantes."
你会用哪个词  国务卿先生
And what word would you use, Mr. Secretary.
"危险"怎么样
How about "dangerous?"
你会如何形容一群驻扎在美国的能力增强者
What would you call a group of US-based, enhanced individuals,
习惯性地无视主权国家边界
who routinely ignores sovereign borders
去哪  做什么  全凭自己意愿
and inflict their will wherever they choose
而且老实说  对造成的后果也似乎毫不关心
and who, frankly, seem unconcerned about what they leave behind.
纽约
New York.
华盛顿特区
Washington D.C.
索科威亚
Sokovia.
拉各斯
Lagos.
好了  够了
Okay. That's enough.
过去四年中
For the past 4 years,
你们的行动拥有无限权力而且无人监管
you've operated with unlimited power and no supervision.
世界各国政府对这种情况
That's an arrangement the governments of the world
已不能再容忍
can no longer tolerate.
但我们有解决办法
But I think we have a solution.
《索科威亚协议》
The Sokovia Accords.
117国批准
Approved by 117 countries.
其中写明  复仇者联盟
It states, that the Avengers
不再是私人组织
shall no longer be a private organization.
而是
Instead,
要在一个联合国小组的监督下行动
they'll operate under the supervision of a United Nations Panel,
且是否出动要由该小组决定
only when and if that Panel deems it necessary.
复仇者联盟的成立是为了让世界更安全
The Avengers were formed to make the world a safer place.
我觉得我们做到了
I feel we've done that.
队长  你知道托尔和班纳现在在哪吗
Tell me Captain, do you know where Thor and Banner are right now?
我要是搞丢了两个30兆吨级的核武器
If I misplaced a couple of 30 megaton nukes,
肯定会有后果
you can bet there'd be consequences.
妥协  保证  世界就是这样运转的
Compromise. Reassurance. That's how the world works.
相信我  这就是中间立场
Believe me, this is the middle ground.
有应急预案的吧
So, there are contingencies.
三天后  联合国将在维也纳召开会议
3 days from now, the UN meets in Vienna
批准《协议》
to ratify the Accords.
你们好好谈谈吧
Well, talk it over.
要是我们的决定你不喜欢呢
And if we come to a decision you don't like?
那你们就退休
Then you retire.
克利夫兰
有人吗
Hello?
外面停的是你的车吗
Is this your car out front?
我开到人行道上了
I jumped the kerb.
也许我们可以私了
Maybe we could, take care of it ourselves.
要是你想打电话叫警察
I mean, if you want to call the cops,
那也可以
that...that's okay too, I guess.
不
No.
不用叫警察
No cops.
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎么没变样  上校
You kept your looks, Colonel.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
任务汇报  1991年12月16日
Mission report: December 16, 1991
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫泽莫
My name is Zemo.
我会重复一遍我的问题
I will repeat my question.
任务汇报  1991年12月16日
Mission report. December 16, 1991
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
神盾局陷落时
When S.H.I.E.L.D. fell,
黑寡妇公布了九头蛇文件
Black Widow released Hydra files to the public.
有数百万页  大都加了密
Millions of pages much of it encrypted.
很难破译
Not easy to decipher.
但是
But,
我有经验
I have experience.
也有耐心
And patience.
有这两样就什么都能做成
A man can do anything if he has those.
你想要什么
What do you want?
任务汇报  1991年12月16日
Mission report. December 16, 1991
见鬼去吧
Go to hell.
九头蛇活该灰飞烟灭
Hydra deserves its place on the ashheap,
所以  我不介意杀你
so your death would not bother me.
但你不说  我就得用这本书
But I'd have to use this book,
和其他更血腥的手段  来找到我要的
and other bloodier methods to find what I need.
我并不想那样
I don't look forward to that.
而你的死  也只是保住了自尊
You'd only be dying for... your pride.
九头蛇万岁
Hail Hydra.
国务卿罗斯有一枚国会荣誉勋章
Secretary Ross, has a Congressional Medal of Honor,
比你多一枚
which is one more than you have.
那么假设我们同意签字
So, let's say we agree to this thing.
政府过多久就会像追踪普通罪犯那样
How long does it gonna be before they LoJack us
追踪我们
like a bunch of common criminals?
117个国家要签这份协议
117 countries want to sign this.
117个  山姆
117, Sam,
你就完全不当回事吗
and you're just like, "No, that's cool. We got it."
你还要做多久两面派
How long are you gonna play both sides?
-我有个方程式  -这样就明白了
- I have an equation. - Oh, this will clear it up.
斯塔克先生宣布他是钢铁侠后的八年里
In the 8 years since Mr. Stark announced himself as Iron Man,
能力增强者的数量一直呈指数增长
the number of known enhanced persons has grown exponentially.
同一段时期里
And during the same period,
可能引发世界末日的事件数量
the number of potentially world-ending events
也在同时上升
has risen at a commensurate rate.
你是说  这是我们的错吗
You saying it's our fault?
我是说  这可能有因果关系
I'm saying there maybe a causality.
我们的超能力招来挑战
Our very strength invites challenge.
挑战激发冲突
Challenge incites conflict.
而冲突
And conflict...
会引发灾难
breeds catastrophe.
监管
Oversight.
是我们应该给予考虑的
Oversight is not an idea that can be dismissed out of hand.
说到点上了
Boom.
托尼  你安静得出奇啊
Tony, you're being uncharacteristically non-hyperverbal.
因为他已经决定好了
It's because he's already made up his mind.
天呐  你真懂我
Boy, you know me so well.
实际上  是电磁头痛犯了
Actually, I'm nursing my electromagnetic headache.
所以我才沉默  队长
That's what's going on, Cap.
就是疼
It's just pain...
不舒服
it's discomfort.
是谁把咖啡渣倒进垃圾处理器了
Who's putting coffee grounds in the disposal?
我是给机车党开了家旅馆吗
Am I running a bed and breakfast for a biker gang?
那是查尔斯·斯宾塞
Oh, that's Charles Spencer by the way.
是个好孩子  计算机工程专业
He's a great kid. Computer engineering degree.
平均成绩3.6
3.6 GPA.
计划秋天去因特尔基层上班
Had a floor-level gig at Intel planned for the fall.
但是  他想趁窝在办公室里之前
But first, he wanted to put a few miles on his soul,
先去积累阅历
before he park it behind a desk.
看看世界  做做义工
See the world, maybe be of service.
查理不想去维加斯或劳德尔堡
Charlie didn't want to go to Vegas or Fort Lauderdale
要我就会选那些地方
which is what I would do.
也没去巴黎或阿姆斯特丹  那儿多有趣
He didn't go to Paris or Amsterdam, which sounds fun.
他想利用暑假
He decided to spend his summer,
给穷人建生态住宅
building sustainable housing for the poor.
猜猜是哪  索科威亚
Guess where, Sokovia.
他可能是想做出些改变
He wanted to make a difference, I suppose.
但我们无从得知了
I mean, we won't know
因为我们打得正高兴时
cause we dropped a building on him
向他身上砸了一栋楼
while we were kicking ass.
我们完全没有决策程序
There's no decision making process here.
我们需要受到管制
We need to be put in check.
不管以什么形式  我都接受
Whatever form that takes, I'm game.
如果不受限制  我们就会无法无天
If we can't accept limitations, if we're bounderless,
比坏人好不到哪去
we're no better than the bad guys.
托尼  有人死在你眼皮下
Tony, someone dies on your watch,
你不能就此放弃
you don't give up.
谁说我们要放弃了
Who said we're giving up?
如果不对自己的行为负责  就是放弃
We are, for not taking responsibility for our actions.
这些文件只是在推卸责任
These documents just shifts the blames.
对不起  史蒂夫
I'm sorry, Steve, that...
这话自负得危险
That is dangerously arrogant.
这可是联合国啊
This is the United Nations we're talking about.
不是世界安全理事会
It's not the World Security Council,
不是神盾局  也不是九头蛇
it's not S.H.I.E.L.D., it's not Hydra.
对  但管理者仍是人  人有目的
No, but it's run by people with agendas
而目的会变
and agendas change.
那是好事  所以我才会在这儿
That's good. That's why I'm here.
当我意识到我的武器落入敌手
When I realized what my weapons were capable of
后果会多不堪设想时
in the wrong hands,
我就停止生产了
I shut it down, stopped manufacturing...
托尼  那是你的选择
Tony. You chose to do that.
如果我们签字  就放弃了选择权
If we sign this, we surrender our right to choose.
如果小组派我们去不该去的地方
What if this Panel sends us somewhere we don't think we should go.
或是不许我们去该去的地方呢
What if there's somewhere we need to go, and they don't let us.
我们也许不完美  但仍是最可靠的人
We may not be perfect, but the safest hands are still our own.
如果现在不签  将来他们会强迫我们签
If we don't do this now, it's going to be done to us later.
事实就是如此  到时会闹得很不好看
That's the fact. That won't be pretty.
-你是说他们会来抓我  -我们会保护你的
- You're saying they'll come for me. - We would protect you.
或许托尼是对的
Maybe Tony's right.
如果我们稍作妥协  就还有回旋余地
If, we have one hand on the wheel we can still steer.
但如果彻底决裂...
If we take it off...
你还是不是
Aren't you the same woman
几年前跟政府叫板的那个女人了
who told the government to kiss her ass a few years ago?
我这是...审时度势
I'm just... reading the terrain.
我们在公众面前犯了些大错
We have made some very public mistakes.
我们需要重获他们的信任
We need to win their trust back.
慢着
Focus up.
抱歉  是我听错了吗  你是在支持我吗
I'm sorry, did I just mishear you or did you agree with me.
-我想反悔了  -不不  不能收回
- Oh, I want to take it back. - No, no, no. You can't retract it.
谢谢啊  真是破天荒
Thank you. Unprecedented.
好了  这事结了
Okay, case close.
她在睡梦中去世了
我赢了
I win.
她在睡梦中去世了
.
我得走了
I have to go.
伦敦
玛格丽特·佩吉·卡特
现在
And now,
我想请莎伦·卡特
I would like to invite Sharon Carter,
上台说几句
to come up and say a few words.
玛格丽特·卡特为人熟知的身份是神盾局创始人
Margaret Carter was known to most as a founder of S.H.I.E.L.D.
但对我来说  她只是佩吉姑妈
But I just knew her as Aunt Peggy.
她办公室有张相片
She had a photograph in her office.
佩吉姑妈跟肯尼迪并肩而站
Aunt Peggy standing next to JFK.
作为孩子  这让我觉得很酷
As a kid, that was pretty cool.
但这也是很大的压力
But, it was a lot to live up to.
所以我从不告诉别人我们是亲戚
Which is why I never told anyone we were related.
有一次我问她
I asked her once
在女性饱受歧视的时代
how she managed to master diplomacy and espionage
她是如何成为一名成功的外交官和间谍的
in a time when no one wanted to see a woman succeed at either.
她回答说  能妥协就妥协
She said, compromise where you can.
不能妥协就坚持己见
But where you can't, don't.
即使你身边所有人
Even if everyone is telling you
都把错的说成对的
that something wrong is something right.
即使全世界都叫你让开
Even if the whole world is telling you to move.
你必须如大树般稳稳站住
It is your duty, to plant yourself like a tree,
直视他们的眼睛说  "不...
look them in they eye and say, "No...
你让开"
... you move."
被解冻后
When I came out of the ice,
我以为我认识的人都死了
I thought everyone I had known was gone.
后来知道她还活着
When I found out that she was alive,
只觉得还有她在很幸运
I was just lucky to have her.
有你也是她的幸运
She had you back too.
还有谁签字了
Who else signed it.
托尼  罗德  幻视
Tony, Rhodey, Vision.
克林特呢
Clint?
他说自己退休了
Says he's retired.
-旺达呢  -待定
- Wanda? - TBD.
我要去维也纳签《协议》
I'm off to Vienna for the signing of the Accords.
飞机上还有好多空位
There's plenty of room on the jet.
这虽然是最轻松的路
Just because it's the path of least resistance
不代表就是错的路
doesn't mean it's the wrong path.
团结比团结的方式更重要
Staying together is more important than how we stay together.
那我们要为此放弃什么
What are we giving up to do it?
抱歉  小娜  我不能签
I'm sorry, Nat. I can't sign it.
我知道
I know.
那你来干吗
Then what are you doing here?
我不想让你一个人面对
I didn't want you to be alone.
过来
Come here.
维也纳
在一次特殊的联合国会议中
At a special United Nations conference,
117个国家一起正式签署了《索科威亚协议》
117 countries have come together to ratify the Sokovia Accords.
-抱歉  请问是罗曼诺夫小姐吗  -是
- Excuse me, Miss Romanoff? - Yes.
需要您签个字
These need your signature.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thanks.
我们俩似乎都不习惯成为焦点人物
I suppose neither of us is used to the spotlight.
毕竟这不总是好事
Well, it's not always so flattering.
你到目前表现得还好嘛
You seem to be doing alright so far.
考虑到你之前在国会山的经历
Considering your last trip to Capitol Hill,
想必你跟这些人待在一起不会很自在
I wouldn't think you'd be particularly comfortable in this company.
确实如此
Well, I'm not.
光是这一点就让我感激你能来  罗曼诺夫小姐
And that alone makes me glad you are here, Ms Romanoff.
为什么  你不赞成此举吗
Why? You don't approve of all this?
《协议》我支持  政治方面就不敢苟同
The Accords, yes. The politics, not really.
两个人在一间屋里  效率能胜过百人
Two people, in a room, can get more done than a 100.
除非你需要搬钢琴
Unless you need to move a piano.
-父亲  -孩子
- Papa. - Son.
-罗曼诺夫小姐  -特查卡国王
- Miss. Romanoff. - King T'Chaka.
请允许我为尼日利亚的事道歉
Please, allow me to apologize for what happened in Nigeria.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你对我们的支持
Thank you for agreeing to all this.
我很遗憾罗杰斯队长今天将缺席
I'm sad to hear that Captain Rogers will not be joining us today.
-我也很遗憾  -请大家就座
- Yes, so am I. - If everyone could please be seated.
会议现在正式开始
This assembly is now in session.
未来在召唤我们了
That is the future calling.
很荣幸
Such a pleasure.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不喜欢外交
For a man who disapproves of diplomacy,
却做得越来越好
you're getting quite good at it.
那就好  父亲
I'm happy, Father.
谢谢
Thank you.
当失窃的瓦坎达振金
When stolen Wakandan vibranium
被用于制造可怕的武器
was used to make a terrible weapon,
我们瓦坎达人被迫质疑我们的遗产
we, in Wakanda, were force to question our legacy.
在尼日利亚遇害的那些男男女女
Those men and women killed in Nigeria,
是前去开展慈善活动
were part of a good will mission
而他们的祖国已在阴影中待了太久
from a country too long in the shadows.
然而  我们不会因不幸而却步
We will not, however, let misfortune drive us back.
我们会努力让我们想走入的世界更加美好
We will fight to improve the world we wish to join.
我非常感激复仇者联盟对此计划的支持
I am grateful to the Avengers for supporting this initiative.
瓦坎达非常骄傲能为和平贡献力量
Wakanda is proud to extend its hand in peace.
大家卧倒
Everybody get down!
我妈妈曾劝我不要入伍  但是...
My mom tried to talk me out of enlisting, but...
但佩吉姑妈没有
not Aunt Peggy.
我的第一个大腿枪套就是她送的
She brought me my first thigh holster.
-非常实用  -还很时髦
- Very practical. - And stylish.
中情局把你派来了这里吗
The CIA has you stationed over here now?
是去柏林  联合反恐任务小组
At Berlin, Joint Terrorism Task Force.
这样啊
Right.
-听起来不错  -可不是
- Sounds fun. - I know, right?
我一直想问你
I've been meaning to ask you.
你在走廊对面监视我的时候
When you were spying on me from across the hall...
你是说我在执行任务的时候
You mean when I was doing my job?
佩吉知道吗
Did Peggy know?
她的秘密已经够多了
She kept so many secrets.
我不希望她还要面对你的秘密
I didn't want her to have one from you.
-谢谢你送我回来  -不客气
- Thanks for walking me back. - Sure.
史蒂夫  你得看看这个
Steve. There's something you got to see.
一枚放在新闻车上的炸弹
A bomb hidden in a news van
-炸毁了位于  -是谁在指挥
- ripped through - Who's coordinating?
维也纳的联合国大楼
the UN building in Vienna.
超过70人受伤  至少12人死亡
More than 70 people have been injured. At least 12 are dead.
联合国大楼遭炸弹袭击
其中包括瓦坎达国王特查卡
Including Wakanda's King T'Chaka.
联合国大楼遭炸弹袭击
当局发布了一段嫌疑人的视频
Officials have released a video of a suspect,
联合国大楼遭炸弹袭击
他们确认此人正是
who they have identified
联合国大楼遭炸弹袭击
冬日战士詹姆斯·布坎南·巴恩斯
as James Buchanan Barnes, the Winter Soldier.
这名臭名昭著的九头蛇特工
The infamous Hydra agent,
与数起恐怖袭击和政治暗杀有牵连
linked to numerous acts of terrorism and political assassinations.
我得去工作了
I have to go to work.
给军情六处打电话
Call MI6
看看能否让微取证小组快速行动
see if we can get Micro Forensics to hurry this up.
两小时内得赶过来  不然就没意义了
We need the whole team here in two hours or it's not worth it.
我非常抱歉
I'm very sorry.
在我的文化里  死亡并不是终结
In my culture, death, is not the end.
更像是  前往陌生领域的起点
It's more of a... stepping-off point.
你向芭丝特与塞赫麦特伸出双手
You reach out with both hands and Bast and Sekhmet,
他们带你走进绿草原  在那里
they lead you into the green veldt where....
你可以永远奔跑下去
you can run forever.
听起来非常安宁
That sounds very peaceful.
我父亲也这样认为
My father thought so.
但是我不是我的父亲
I am not my father.
特查拉
T'Challa.
特遣队会决定谁去抓巴恩斯
Task Force will decide who brings in Barnes.
不用麻烦了  罗曼诺夫小姐
Don't bother, Miss. Romanoff.
我会亲手杀了他
I'll kill him myself.
-喂  -你还好吗
- Yeah? - Are you alright?
还行  谢谢关心  我挺幸运的
Ah, yeah, thanks. I..I got lucky.
我知道你多在乎巴恩斯  真的
I know how much Barnes means to you. I really do.
待在家里  别出来
Stay home.
你只会让局面更糟  让我们都不好做  求你
You'll only make this worse for all of us. Please.
-你是说你要逮捕我吗  -不
- Are you saying you'll arrest me? - No.
如果你出手  会有人抓你的  现在就是这样了
Someone will, if you interfere. That's how it works now.
要是他都变成这样了  小娜
If he's this far gone, Nat,
那就该由我去抓他
I should be the one to bring him in.
为什么
Why?
因为我是最不可能因此丧命的人
Because I'm the one least likely to die trying.
该死
Shit.
她叫你别插手吗
She tell you to stay out of it?
-她或许有些道理  -他也会为我出手的
- Might have a point. - He'd do it for me.
要在1945年  有可能
1945, maybe.
我只是想确认我们考虑周全了
I just want to make sure we consider all our options.
冲你开枪的人  通常最终也会冲我开枪
The people that shoot at you, usually wind up shooting at me.
录像公布后收到了很多线报
Tips have been pouring in since that footage went public.
人人都觉得冬日战士跟他们去一家健身房
Everybody thinks the Winter Soldier goes to their gym.
大部分线索都没有价值  除了这一条
Most of it is noise, except for this.
我的上司现在就要简报
My boss expects a briefing pretty much now,
只能给你这么多情报了
so that's all the answer you're gonna get.
-谢谢  -你得抓紧时间
- Thank you. - And you're going to have to hurry.
我们的命令是当场击毙
We have orders to shoot on sight.
回祖国
Homecoming.
一
One.
火车货车车厢
Freight car.
穆勒先生
Mr. Muller.
您的早餐
I have your breakfast.
隔着门就闻到了
I could smell it before I opened the door.
熏猪肋肉和黑咖啡
Side of bacon and black coffee.
还是老样子
Again.
如果您需要  我可以做点儿别的
I can make you something different, if you like.
这就很好
This is wonderful...
我帮您端到...
I will just put this on your...
没关系  我自己来就好
It's okay, I can manage!
-这个怎么样  -很好的
那好
那我要六个
给你  谢谢
布加勒斯特
冬日战士因维也纳爆炸事件被通缉
注意  队长
Heads up, Cap.
德国特种部队从南面过来了
German special forces approaching from the south.
收到
Understood.
你认得我吗
Do you know me?
你是史蒂夫
You're Steve.
我在博物馆里了解过你
I read about you in a museum.
他们设置了警戒线
They've set the perimeter.
我知道你有点紧张
I know you're nervous.
你也有理由紧张
And you have plenty of reason to be.
但你在撒谎
But you're lying.
我没去维也纳  我不做那种事了
I wasn't in Vienna. I don't do that anymore.
他们进入大楼了
They're entering the building.
认为是你的人要来了
Well, the people who think you did are coming here now.
他们没准备留你活口
And they're not planning on taking you alive.
很聪明  这招不错
That's smart. Good strategy.
他们上楼顶了  我得撤了
They're on the roof. I'm compromised.
我们不非得打起来  巴基
This doesn't have end in a fight, Buck.
-总是要打起来的  -还有5秒
- It always ends in a fight. - 5 seconds.
你从河里救我出来  为什么
You pulled me from the river. Why?
-不知道  -3秒
- I don't know. - 3 seconds!
你知道的
Yes, you do.
突破  突破  突破
Breach! Breach! Breach!
把门炸开
巴基  住手
Buck, stop!
你会杀死谁的
You're gonna kill someone.
我谁都不会杀
I'm not gonna kill anyone.
嫌犯已逃跑
Suspect has broken containment!
他顺东楼梯井下去了
He's headed down the east stairwell!
拜托  伙计
Come on, man.
-山姆  去西南屋顶  -另一个人是谁
- Sam, southwest rooftop. - Who the hell is the other guy?
马上就知道了
About to find out.
-山姆  -我来
- Sam. - Got it.
站住
Stand down!
-山姆  我甩不掉这人
- Sam, I can't shake this guy.
-就来
- Right behind you.
立刻投降
Stand down. Now.
恭喜你  队长  你是罪犯了
Congratulations, Cap. You're a criminal.
国王殿下
Your Highness.
放少许辣椒粉
A pinch of paprika.
少许是多少
A pinch.
那是辣椒粉吗
Is that paprikash?
我想这或许能让你振奋精神
I thought it might... lift your spirits.
精神振奋了
Spirits lifted.
不好意思  我从来没有
In my defense, I..I haven't actually ever...
-没吃过东西  -能让我来吗
- ...eaten anything before, so... - May I.
请吧
Please.
旺达
Wanda.
没人讨厌你
No one dislikes you, Wanda.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - Oh, you're welcome.
我的意思是
No. It's a...
这是杏仁体的一种下意识反应
involuntary response in their amygdala
他们控制不住害怕你
they can't help but be afraid of you.
你也怕我吗
Are you?
我的杏仁体是人造的  所以
My amygdala is synthetic, so...
我以前对自己有一定的看法
I used to think of myself one way.
但是  自从有了异能
But, after this.
我就变了
I am something else.
我还是那个我
I'm still me, I think.
但世人不这么看了
But... that's not what everyone else sees.
我不知道这是什么东西
Do you know, I don't know what this is.
并不清楚
Not really.
它不属于这个世界
I know it's not of this world.
它给洛基的权杖供能
But it powered Loki staff,
也让你拥有了异能  但是
gave you your abilities. But...
它的真正属性依然未知
its true nature is a mystery.
而它是我的一部分
And yet, it is part of me.
你怕它吗
Are you afraid of it?
我想了解它
I wish to understand it.
我越了解它  它对我的控制就越小
The more I do, the less it controls me.
或许有天  我还能控制它
One day, who knows, I may even control it.
我不知道这是什么  但肯定不是辣椒粉
I don't know what's in this but it is not paprika.
我去趟商店  20分钟就回来
I'm gonna go to the store, I'll be back in 20 minutes.
或者  我们可以订披萨
Alternatively, we could order a pizza?
幻视  你是不让我离开吗
Vision, are you not letting me leave?
-是为了安全起见  -我能保护自己
- It is a question of safety. - I can protect myself.
不是你的安全
Not yours.
斯塔克先生想避免
Mr. Stark would like to avoid the possibility
再发生公开事故
of another public incident,
直到《协议》基本尘埃落定
until the Accords are of a... more secured foundation.
那你想要什么
And what do you want?
世人像我那样看待你
For people to see you... as I do.
柏林
-那么  你喜欢猫吗  -山姆
- So, you like cats? - Sam.
怎么  这家伙穿得像个猫
What? Dude shows up dressed like a cat
你不好奇吗
and you don't wanna know more?
你的衣服  是振金做的吗
Your suit. It's Vibranium?
黑豹世代是瓦坎达的守护者
The Black Panther has been the protector of Wakanda for generations.
是战士代代相传的衣钵
A mantle passed from warrior to warrior.
现在  因为你朋友杀了我父亲
And now because your friend murdered my father,
我也继承了国王的衣钵
I also wear the Mantle of King.
我倒要问你
So I ask you,
既作为战士  又是国王
as both warrior and King,
你觉得你还能保护你朋友多久
how long do you think you can keep your friend safe from me?
要怎么处置他
What's gonna happen?
按说你们也该跟他一样
Same thing that ought to happen to you.
进行心理评估  然后引渡
Psychological evaluation and extradition.
这位是埃弗雷特·罗斯
This is Everett Ross,
特遣队副指挥官
Deputy Task Force Commander.
-那律师呢  -律师  真可笑
- What about a lawyer. - Lawyer, that's funny.
把他们的武器锁好
See their weapons are placed in lock up.
我们会给你写收据的
Oh, we'll write you a receipt.
最好别让我看到
I better not look out the window
有人穿着我的装备在飞
and see anybody flying around in that.
我们会为您提供办公室  不会让您进牢房
You'll be provided with an office instead of a cell.
拜托您留在办公室里
And do me a favour, stay in it.
我哪也不打算去
I don't intend on going anywhere.
顺便说一句  这就是更糟的局面
For the record. This is what making things worse looks like.
至少他还活着
He's alive.
不不
No.
罗马尼亚不受《协议》保护
Romania was not Accords-sanctioned.
罗德中校在监督善后工作
Colonel Rhodes is supervising clean up.
我们处理问题期间别再惹麻烦了
Try not to break anything while we fix this.
问责吗  当然要问责了
Consequences? You bet there'll be consequences.
你当然可以引用我刚刚说的话
Obviously you can quote me on that cause I just said it.
还有事吗  谢谢你  先生
Anything else? Thank you, sir.
问责
Consequences?
国务卿罗斯想起诉你们俩
Secretary Ross wants you both prosecuted.
我总得拿点什么嘟他的嘴
Had to give him something.
我拿不回盾牌了吧
I'm not getting that shield back, am I?
严格说  那是政府财产
Technically, it's the government's property.
-鹰翼也是  -太冷酷了
- Wings too. - That's cold.
总比监狱温暖
Warmer than jail.
不会吧  搞什么
你想看点厉害的东西吗
Hey, you want to see something cool?
我从老爸的档案馆里找到的
I pulled something from dad's archives.
感觉时机正合适
Felt timely.
罗斯福1941年签《租借法案》时用的
FDR signed the Lend-Lease bill with these in 1941.
为急需帮助的盟军提供了支持
Provided support to the Allies when they needed it most.
有人会说这让我们国家靠近了战争
Someone would say it brought our country closer to war.
如果不是因为这对笔  你就不会在这儿了
See, if not for these, you wouldn't be here.
我是想  该怎么说
I'm trying to, what do you call it?
这是橄榄枝  是这么说的吗
That's an olive branch. Is that what you call it?
派珀来了吗  我没见着她
Is Pepper here? I didn't see her.
我们算是...
We are... kinda...
-好吧  其实就是  -有喜了
- well not kinda... - Pregnant?
不  绝对没有  我们分手了
No, definitely not. We're taking a break.
谁都没有错
It's nobody's fault.
抱歉  托尼  我不知道
I'm so sorry, Tony. I didn't know.
几年前我差点失去她
A few years ago, I almost lost her,
于是我毁了我所有的战甲
so I trashed all my suits.
然后我们不得不对付九头蛇
Then, we had to mop up Hydra.
之后又是奥创  这怪我
And then Ultron, my fault.
之后事情一件又一件  我一直没停下
And then, and then, and then. I never stopped.
因为事实就是我不想停
Cause the truth is I don't wanna stop.
我不想失去她
I don't want to lose her.
我想或许《协议》是个折衷的办法
I thought maybe the Accords could split the difference.
替她说一句  我很难搞
In her defense, I'm a handful.
但我爸也不让人省心
Yet, dad was a pain in the ass, but
可他和我妈却很美满
he and mom always made it work.
我很高兴霍华德结婚了
You know, I'm glad Howard got married.
我只见过年轻单身的他
I only knew him when he was young and single.
真的吗  你们认识啊
Oh really? You two knew each other?
他从没提过  可能就提过一千次吧
He never mentioned that. Maybe only a thousand times.
天啊  我以前真恨你
God, I hated you.
我不是有意让你为难
I don't mean to make things difficult.
我知道  因为你是个非常有礼貌的人
I know. Because you're a very polite person.
如果我觉得情况不妙  我没法无视
If I see a situation pointed south, I can't ignore it.
-有时我希望我能  -你才不呢
- Sometimes I wish I could. - No, you don't.
是啊  我不
No, I don't.
有时
Sometimes...
有时我真想一拳揍在你完美的牙上
Sometimes I wanna punch you in your perfect teeth.
但我不希望你离开
But I don't wanna see you gone.
我们需要你  队长
We need you, Cap.
现在还没出什么不可挽回的事
So far nothing's happened that can't be undone,
只要你签字
if you sign.
我们可以把这24小时的行动合法化
We can make the last 24 hours legit.
巴恩斯会被转移到一家美国精神病中心
Barnes gets transferred to an American psych center
而不是瓦坎达监狱
instead of a Wakandan prison.
也不是绝对不行  但是
I'm not saying it's impossible. But
得有保障措施
there would have to be safeguards.
当然
Sure.
等公关处理好了  这些文件都可以修订
Once we put out the PR fire, these documents can be amended.
我已经提议让你和旺达复职
I filed a motion to have you and Wanda reinstated.
-旺达  旺达怎么了  -她很好
- Wanda? What about Wanda? - She's fine.
她现在被禁足在基地
She's confined to the compound currently.
幻视在陪着她
Vision's keeping her company.
天哪  托尼  总是这样
Oh, God, Tony! Every time.
每次我以为你
Every time I think you
-明理  -怎么了  100英亩的房子
- see things the right way... - What? It's a 100 acres
还带小泳池
with a lap pool.
放映室  这样保护人已经很好了
It's got a screening room. There's worse ways to protect people.
保护  你是这么觉得吗
Protection? Is that how you see this?
这是保护吗  这是拘禁  托尼
This is protection? It's internment, Tony.
她不是美国公民
She's not a US citizen.
-拜托  托尼  -他们可不会给
- Oh, come on, Tony. - And they don't grant visas
大规模杀伤性武器批签证
to Weapons of Mass Destruction.
-她还是个孩子  -饶了我吧
- She's a kid! - Give me a break!
只有这样做
I'm doing what has to be done
才能避免我们更糟的处境
... to stave off something worse.
你就继续自欺欺人吧
You keep telling yourself that.
一对儿的别分开
Hate to break up the set.
你好  巴恩斯先生
Hello, Mr. Barnes.
我是受联合国指派来评估你的
I've been sent by the United Nations to evaluate you.
我能坐下吗
Do you mind if I sit?
你的名字是詹姆斯吗
Your first name is James?
你装备的收据
The receipt for your gear.
鸟服装  拜托
Bird costume? Come on.
不是我写的
I didn't write it.
保密
我不是来指责你的
I'm not here to judge you.
我只想问你几个问题
I just want to ask you a few questions.
你知道你在哪里吗  詹姆斯
Do you know where you are, James?
你不跟我说话  我就没法帮你  詹姆斯
I can't help you if you don't talk to me, James.
我叫巴基
My name is Bucky.
有人吗
Hello?
我来送个大家伙
好的
Okay.
给  就在这儿签
Here. Just sign here.
-这里吗  -对
- Here? - Yeah.
特遣队为什么要公布这张照片
Why would the task force release this photo to begin with?
把消息传出去  让更多人来找
Get the word out, involve as many eyes as we can?
是啊
Right.
这是逼的人没法藏身的好方法
It's a good way to flush a guy out of hiding.
引爆炸弹  被人拍到
Set off a bomb, get your picture taken.
让七百万人寻找冬日战士
Get 7 billion people looking for the Winter soldier.
你是说有人为找他而陷害他
You're saying someone framed him to find him.
史蒂夫  我们找了他两年都一无所获
Steve, we looked for the guy for 2 years and found nothing.
我们没炸联合国  这可非常引人注目
We didn't bomb the UN. That turns a lot of heads.
对  但这不能保证
Yeah. But that doesn't guarantee
陷害他的人能找到他
that whoever framed him would get him,
只能保证我们会找到他
it guarantees that we would.
是啊
Yeah.
告诉我  巴基
Tell me Bucky.
你目睹了很多事  对吧
You've seen a great deal, haven't you?
我不想说
I don't want to talk about it.
你觉得
You feel that...
你一旦开口  恐怖就无法停止了
if you open your mouth, the horrors might never stop.
别担心
Don't worry.
包裹已送达
我们只谈一件事
We only have to talk about one.
这是什么
What is this?
赶紧的  各位  让我看到巴恩斯
Alright. Come on, guys. Get me eyes on Barnes.
快  快
Go. Go.
星期五  能查到电力中断的源头吗
F.R.I.D.A.Y. Can you get me a source on that outage?
东地下5层
Sub-level 5, east wing.
-怎么回事  -我们来谈谈你的家乡吧
- What the hell is this? - Why don't we discuss your home?
不是罗马尼亚  也不是布鲁克林
Not Romania. Certainly not Brooklyn, no.
我是说  你真正的家
I mean, your real home.
渴望
Longing
不要
No.
生锈
Rusted
快停下
Stop.
十七
Seventeen
停下
Stop.
黎明
Daybreak
火炉
Furnace
九
Nine
善良
Benign
回祖国
Homecoming
一
One
火车货车车厢
Freight car
士兵
Soldier
愿意服从
Ready to comply.
任务汇报  1991年12月16日
Mission report. December 16, 1991
帮帮我
Help me.
帮帮忙
Help?
起来
Get up.
你是谁  你想干什么
Who are you? What do you want?
毁灭一个帝国
To see an empire fall.
疏散所有民众
Evac all civilians.
在大楼周围拉起警戒  派出武装直升机
Get me a perimeter around the building and gunships in the air.
你带战衣[西装]了吧
Please tell me you brought a suit.
当然带了 汤姆·福特的
Sure did. It's a lovely Tom Ford,
三件套  两扣
three-Piece, 2 button...
我现在是现役非战斗人员
I'm a active duty, non combatant.
跟我来
Follow me.
我们就位了
We're in position.
你至少还认得我吧
You could at least recognise me.
该死
Damn it.
他又问了我一次  你会不会来
He asked me again if you're going to be there?
我说我不知道
I said I wasn't sure.
你真该看到他那张小脸  尽量赶回来  好吗
You should've seen his little face. Just try, okay?
我要睡了  我爱你
I'm going to bed. I love you.
维也纳联合国爆炸案的嫌疑人詹姆斯·巴恩斯
James Barnes the suspect in the UN Vienna bombing...
今日脱逃羁押
escaped custody today.
同时失踪的还有复仇者史蒂夫·罗杰斯队长
Also missing Avenger Captain Steve Rogers...
和山姆·威尔逊
and Sam Wilson.
莫斯科
队长
Hey, Cap!
史蒂夫
Steve.
是哪一个巴基在说话
Which Bucky am I talking to?
你妈妈的名字叫萨拉
Your mom's name is Sarah.
你以前会往鞋里垫报纸
You used to wear newspapers in your shoes.
博物馆里可不会讲这个
Can't read that in a museum.
这就行了  就没事了
Just like that, we're suppose to be cool?
-我做了什么  -不少
- What did I do? - Enough.
天哪  我就知道会这样
Oh god, I knew this would happen.
九头蛇给我灌输的东西都还在
Everything Hydra put inside me is still there.
他只要说几个词就能激发
All he had to do was say the god damn words.
-他是谁  -我不知道
- Who was he? - I don't know.
那场陷害你的爆炸  害死了很多人
People are dead. The bombing. The set up.
那个医生大费周章  就为跟你待上10分钟
The doctor did all that just to get 10 minutes with you.
你不能只说句"我不知道"
I need you to do better than "I don't know."
他想知道西伯利亚的事
He wanted to know about Siberia.
我被关押的地方
Where I was kept.
他想知道具体位置
He wanted to know exactly where.
他为什么要知道这个
Why would he need to know that?
因为冬日战士不止我一个
Because I'm not the only Winter Soldier.
很好
Good work.
带我出去
Get me out of here.
-他们是谁  -精英敢死队
- Who were they? - Their most elite death squad.
九头蛇史上杀人数最多的
More kills than anyone in Hydra history.
那还是在注射血清之前
And that was before the serum.
他们都变得跟你一样吗
They all turned out like you?
更糟
Worse.
那个医生能控制他们吗
The doctor, can he control them?
八九不离十
Enough.
他说他想毁灭一个帝国
Said he wanted to see an empire fall.
有那些人的帮助  他就做得到
With these guys he could do it.
他们会30种语言  来去不着痕迹
They speak 30 languages, can hide in plain sight,
渗透  暗杀  颠覆
infiltrate, assassinate, destabilize,
他们能在一夜之间毁灭一个国家
they can take a whole country down in one night.
打得你措手不及
You'd never see them coming.
搁在一周前这事会简单得多
This would've been a lot easier a week ago.
如果我们告诉托尼
If we call Tony.
-他不会相信的  -即便他信
- No, he won't believe us. - Even if he did...
谁知道《协议》会不会允许他帮忙
Who knows if the Accords would let him help.
我们只能靠自己
We're on our own.
未必
Maybe not.
我认识一个人
I know a guy.
我猜你不知道他们在哪吧
I don't suppose you have any idea where they are.
会知道的  边防9队守着国界
We will. GSG-9's got the borders covered.
侦察机也在全天候搜查
Recons flying 24/7.
他们会有发现  我们就去处理
They'll get a hit. We'll handle it.
你不明白  斯塔克  这事不归你处理
You don't get it, Stark. It's not yours to handle.
你显然无法客观对待此事
It's clear you can't be objective.
我要让特种部队负责
I'm putting special ops on this.
如果交上了火怎么办
And what happens when the shooting starts?
你要杀了史蒂夫·罗杰斯吗
What, do you kill Steve Rogers?
如果他不乖乖就范
If we're provoked.
要不是罗杰斯  我们在罗马尼亚
Barnes would've been eliminate in Romania
就能消灭巴恩斯了
if it wasn't for Rogers.
有些本不该死的人因此丧命
There are dead people who would be alive now.
你倒想想我说没说错
Feel free to check my math.
无意冒犯
All due respect,
这事凭武力是解决不了的  罗斯
you're not gonna solve this with boys and bullets, Ross.
你得让我们去抓他
You got to let us bring him in.
这次和上次又会有什么不同
How would that end any differently than last time?
这次我不会穿便装行动
Because this time I won't be wearing Loafers and a silk shirt.
72小时  我保证
72 hours, guarantee.
36小时
36 hours.
巴恩斯
Barnes.
罗杰斯
Rogers.
威尔逊
Wilson.
多谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
我左手臂麻了  这是正常现象吗
My left arm is numb, is that normal?
你还好吗
You alright?
没事
Always.
36小时  天啊
36 hours, jeez.
-我们人手严重不足  -是啊
- We're seriously understaffed. - Oh, yeah.
如果绿巨人在就好了  有他的线索吗
It would be great if we had a hulk, right about now. Any shot?
你真觉得他会站我们这边吗
You really think he'd be on our side?
不会
No.
-我有个主意  -我也是
- I have an idea. - Me too.
-你的在哪  -楼下
- Where's yours? - Downstairs.
你的呢
Where's yours?
皇后区
梅婶婶
Hey, May.
-今天学校顺利吗  -还不错
- How was school today? - It was okay.
有辆豪车停在外面...
This crazy car parked outside...
帕克先生
Oh, Mr. Parker.
你怎么在这里...
What... What are you doing...?
我是彼得
I'm-I'm-I'm Peter.
-我是托尼  -你...
- Tony. - What are...
你在这里做什么
What are you-What are you- What are you doing here?
我们该见见了  你收到我邮件了吧
It's about time we met. You've been getting my e-mails, right?
-收到了吧  -收到了
- Right? - Yeah. Yeah.
-关于...  -你没告诉我基金的事
- Regarding the... - You didn't tell me about the grant.
-基金的事  -九月基金
- About the grant. - The September Foundation.
-没错  -记得你申请了吗
- Right. - Yeah. Remember when you applied.
-记得  -我批准了
- Yeah. - I approved.
这事现在就算成了
So now, we're in business.
你都没告诉过我  这是怎么回事
You didn't tell me anything. What's up with that?
-你现在还瞒我事了吗  -我只是...
- You're keeping secrets from me? - Why, I just...
我知道你很喜欢惊喜
I just know how much you love surprises,
所以我想等回头再告诉你
so I thought I would let you know... wh...
话说回来  我申请了什么
Anyway, what did I apply for?
这就是我来要解决的事
That's what I'm here to hash out.
好  解决  好吧
Okay, hash, hash out, okay.
她居然都当婶婶了  简直难以置信
It's so hard for me to believe that she's someone's aunt.
对啊  什么样的婶婶都有嘛
Yeah well, we come in all shapes and sizes, you know.
这个核桃红枣面包太好吃了
This walnut date loaf is exceptional.
-能先停停吗  -怎么了
- Let me just stop you there. - Yeah?
这个基金  是跟钱有关的吗
Is this grant, like, got money involved or whatever? No?
没错
Yeah.
-没错  -资金非常充足
- Yeah. - It's pretty well funded.
也不看看我是谁
Look who you're talking to.
-我能跟他谈五分钟吗  -请便
- Can I have 5 minutes with him? - Sure.
作为核桃红枣面包  这味道还不错了
As walnut date loaves go, that wasn't bad.
这是什么  复古科技吗
What do we have here, retro tech, huh?
-二手店  救世军  -捡的垃圾
- Thrift store? Salvation army? - Uh, the garbage actually.
-你是捡垃圾的  -对  我是...
- You're a dumpster diver. - Yeah, I was...
随便了  那个
Anyway, look.
我绝对没申请过你的基金
I definitely did not apply for your grant.
-我先说  -好吧
- Me first. - Okay.
有个反问的问题要问你
Quick question of the rhetorical variety.
这是你吧
That's you, right?
不是
Um, no.
-你什么意思  -就是你
- What do you. What do you... - Yeah.
看你的动作
Look at you go.
接得漂亮  时速40英里  三千磅的车
Wow, nice catch! 3000 pounds. 40 miles an hour.
这可不容易  你很厉害啊
It's not easy. You got mad skills.
这是油管上的吧  对吗
That's all-That's all on Youtube though, right?
你是在那儿找到的吧
I mean that's where you found it.
这些可都是假的  是电脑特效
Cause' you know that's all fake. It's all done on a computer?
就像那个视频一样  什么来着
It's like that video, what is it?
对对  就像凤凰城上空的飞碟吗
Yeah yeah yeah... you mean like those UFOs over Phoenix?
没错
Exactly!
这是什么
What have we here?
这是...
That's a...
那么
So.
你是蜘蛛...娃
You're the... Spider..Ling.
打击犯罪蜘蛛...蜘蛛男孩
Crime Fighting Spider... You're Spider-Boy?
蜘蛛侠
S... Spider-Man.
就穿这连体睡衣  还叫侠
Not in that onesie, you're not.
这不是连体睡衣
It's not a onesie.
难以置信
I don't believe this.
我今天其实还真挺顺利的呢  斯塔克先生
I was actually having a real good day today, you know, Mr. Stark.
没误地铁
Didn't miss my trains.
毫不费力地捡到一台质量很好的DVD机
This perfectly good DVD player was just sitting there and...
代数考试也轻松搞定
Algebra test. Nailed it!
还有谁知道  有人知道吗
Who else knows? Anybody?
没人了
Nobody.
连你那位异常迷人的婶婶也不知道吗
Not even your... unusually attractive Aunt?
不
No.
不知道
No, no. No, no.
如果她知道  她会抓狂的
If she knew, she would freak out.
她抓狂  我就慌乱
And when she freaks out, I freak out.
知道我觉得什么很厉害吗  这个网
You know what I think is really cool? This webbing.
抗拉强度简直爆表
Tensile strength is off the charts.
-是谁制造的  -我
- Who manufactured them? - I did.
爬墙
Climbing the walls.
怎么做到的  粘性手套吗
How are you doing that? Adhesive gloves?
说来话长  我...
It's a long story. I was uh...
老天爷  戴这东西还能看见吗
Lordy! Can you even see in these?
-是的  我能看见  -我瞎了
- Yes. Yes, I can! I can. - I'm blind!
能看见的  好吗  就是...
I can-I can see in those. Okay? It's just that...
那件事发生之后
when...whatever happened happened,
我的感官变得超级敏感
it's like my senses have been dialed to 11.
接收的信息实在太多
There's... There's way too much input, so...
所以戴那个能帮我集中注意
they... they just kinda help me focus.
你继续升级装备
You're in dire need of an upgrade.
从头到脚  系统化地升级
Systemic, top to bottom.
全部翻新  我就是为此而来
100-point restoration. That's why I'm here.
你为什么要做这个
Why are you doing this?
我必须要问问  你的动力是什么
I got to know. What's your M.O.
是什么激励你早上起床
What gets you out of that twin bed in the morning?
因为
Because...
因为我这辈子一直都是平凡的自己
because I've been me my whole life,
六个月前我得到了这些能力
and I've had these powers for 6 months.
我读书  搭建电脑
I read books, I build computers...
还有  我很想去打橄榄球
And-And yeah. I would love to play football.
但我之前打不了  所以现在又不能去
But I couldn't then so I shouldn't now.
-是啊  因为你变了  -没错
- Sure. 'Cause you're different. - Exactly.
但我不能说出去  所以我没说
But I can't tell anybody that, so I'm not.
如果你有了这份能力
Look, when you can do the things that I can,
却不作为
but you don't...
之后发生的坏事
and then the bad things happen,
就是你的责任
they happen because of you.
你想帮助小人物  你想尽一份力
So you wanna look out for the little guy. You wanna do your part.
让这世界更美好什么的  是吗
Make the world a better place all that, right?
是啊  就是帮助小人物
Yeah. Yeah just looking out... for the little guy.
就是这样
That's-That's what it is.
我要坐这儿  腿移开
I'm going to sit here, so you move the leg.
-有护照吗  -没有
- You got a passport? - Uh, no.
我连驾照都没有
I don't.. don't even have a driving license.
去过德国吗
You ever been to Germany?
-没有  -你会喜欢那里的
- No. - Oh, you'll love it.
-我不能去德国  -为什么
- I can't go to Germany! - Why?
我还有作业呢
I got... homework.
好吧  我会当你没说那话
Alright, I'm gonna pretend you didn't say that.
不  我认真的  我不能就辍学
No. I'm-I'm being serious! I can't just drop out of school!
可能会有点危险
Might be a little dangerous.
最好跟漂亮婶婶说一声我要带你出去
Better tell Aunt Hottie I'm taking you on a field trip.
别告诉梅婶婶
Don't tell Aunt May.
好吧  蜘蛛侠
Alright, Spider-Man.
-给我解开  -抱歉  我这就弄
- Get me out of this. - I'm sorry, I'll get that.
-怎么回事  -请待在这里
- What is it? - Stay here, please.
-看来我该敲门的  -天呐
- Guess I should have knocked. - Oh my god.
-你来做什么  -放孩子的鸽子
- What are you doing here? - Disappointing my kids.
我本该带他们去滑水的
I'm suppose to go water skiing.
但是队长需要我们帮忙  走吧
But Cap needs our help, come on.
克林特
Clint!
你不该来的
You should not be here.
是吗
Really?
我才退休了5分钟  世界就乱套了
I retired for, what, like 5 minutes? And it all goes to shit.
请考虑一下你行为的后果
Please consider the consequences of your actions.
考虑过了
Okay, they're considered.
好了  我们得走了
Okay, we got to go.
是这边
It's this way.
我闯的祸够多了
I've caused enough problems.
你得帮帮忙  旺达
You got to help me, Wanda.
你要闷闷不乐不如去上高中
Look you want to mope you can go to high school.
你想弥补  就给我行动起来
You want to make amends. You get off your ass.
该死
Shit.
就知道我该先活动下筋骨的
I know I should have stretched.
-克林特  你打不过我  -我知道
- Clint, you can't overpower me. - I know I can't
但她能
But, she can.
幻视  够了  放了他
Vision. That's enough, let him go.
-我要走了  -我不能让你走
- I'm leaving. - I can't let you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
如果你这么做
If you do this,
世人会永远害怕你
they will never stop being afraid of you.
他们的恐惧我控制不了  但我的可以
I can't control their fear, only my own.
走吧  还有一站呢
Come on. We got one more stop.
早晚会找到的
It's just a matter of time.
我们的卫星在进行面部识别
Our satellites are running facial,
生物识别和行为模式扫描
biometric and behavioral pattern scans.
闪开  别逼我动手
Move, or you will be moved.
虽然那会很有看头
As entertaining as that would be.
你真觉得你能找到他吗
You really think you can find him?
我的资源很可观
My resources are considerable.
是啊  世界花了70年时间才找到巴恩斯
Yeah, it took the world 70 years to find Barnes...
你大概花一半时间就能做到了
So, you could probably do that in about half the time.
你知道他们在哪
You know where they are.
我认识一个知道的人
I know someone who does.
你恐怕不太明白什么叫逃跑车吧
I'm not sure you understand the concept of a get-away car.
这车低调
It's low profile.
很好  这些东西可是很招眼
Good, 'cause this stuff tends to draw a crowd.
-你能把座椅往前点吗  -不能
- Can you move your seat up? - No.
我又欠你个人情
I owe you again.
我记着呢
Keeping a list.
他之前可企图杀我呢
You know, he kind of tried to kill me.
抱歉  那个我也会记着的
Sorry, I'll put it on the list, too.
他们会来找你的
They're gonna come looking for you.
我知道
I know.
谢谢你  莎伦
Thank you, Sharon.
-这真是  -早该了
- That was... - Late.
可不是
Damn right.
-我该走了  -好
- I should go. - Okay.
队长
Cap.
你知道我不是别无选择也不会找你
You know I wouldn't have called If I had any other choice.
你是帮我忙呢
Hey man, you're doing me a favour.
再说  我还要还债
Besides... I owed a debt.
-多谢支持我  -我该行动起来了
- Thanks for having my back. - It was time to get off my ass.
另一个新人呢
How about our other recruit.
他迫不及待呢
He's raring to go.
我给了他点咖啡
Had to put a little coffee in him... but
他应该没问题
he should be good.
这是哪个时区
What timezone is this?
去吧  去吧
Come on. Come on.
-美国队长  -朗先生
- Captain America. - Mr. Lang.
真是荣幸  我握得太久了
It's an honor. I'm shaking your hand too long.
这太赞了  美国队长啊
This is awesome. Captain America.
你我也认识  你好棒
I know you too, you're great.
天呐
Jeez.
我想说
Look, I wanted to say.
我知道你认识很多厉害人物
I know you know a lot of super people, so...
多谢想到我
Thanks for thinking of me.
-伙计  -好啊  小豆子
- Hey, man. - What's up tic-tac.
见到你很高兴  那个  上次的事
Good to see you. Look. Look, what happened last time when I...
是场很棒的面试  但绝不会再有下次了
It was a great audition, but it'll... it'll never happen again.
他们告诉你我们要对付什么了吗
They tell you what we're up against?
好像是几个疯子刺客
Something about some... psycho assassins.
这次我们的行动不合法
We're outside the law on this one.
如果你跟我们来  就是通缉犯了
So, if you come with us, you're a wanted man.
早习惯了
Yeah, well, what else is new?
-我们该走了  -有架直升机等着我们呢
- We should get moving. - We got a chopper lined up.
他们在疏散机场
They're evacuating the airport.
-斯塔克  -斯塔克
- Stark. - Stark?
换装
Suit up.
在机场总能碰到熟人  真是怪啊
It's so weird how you run into people at the airport.
-你说是不是  -非常怪
- Don't you think that's weird? - Definitely weird.
听我说  托尼
Hear me out, Tony.
那个精神病医生  他才是幕后黑手
That doctor, the psychiatrist, he's behind all of this.
-队长  -殿下
- Captain. - Your Highness.
总之
Anyway.
罗斯给了我36小时带你回去
Ross gave me 36 hours to bring you in.
已经过了24小时了
That was 24 hours ago.
-帮兄弟一把啊  -你抓错人了
- Can you help a brother out? - You're after the wrong guy.
你的判断力有问题
Your judgment is askew.
你的老战友昨天杀了很多无辜者
Your old war buddy killed innocent people yesterday.
还有5个跟他一样的超级战士
And there are 5 more super soldiers just like him.
我不能让那个医生先找到他们  托尼
I can't let the doctor find them first, Tony. I can't.
史蒂夫
Steve.
你知道接下来会怎么样
You know, what's about to happen.
你这次也要打出一条血路吗
Do you really want to punch your way out of this one?
好吧  我没耐心了
All right, I've run out of patience.
内衣宝宝
Underoos!
干得好  孩子
Nice job, kid.
谢谢  落地不太理想
Thanks. Well, I could've stuck the landing a little better.
新服装...不太适应
It's... just the new suit...
等等  这不是事儿  斯塔克先生
Wait, it's nothing, Mr. Stark.
服装很完美  谢谢您
It's-It's perfect, thank you.
嗯  我们不用开始闲扯的
Yeah, we don't really need to start a conversation.
好吧  队长
Okay. Cap... Captain.
我是蜘蛛侠  你的大粉丝
Big fan, I'm Spider-Man.
行了  回头再说
Yeah, we'll talk about it later. Just...
-大家好  -干得好
- Hey, everyone. - ...good job.
-你没闲着啊  -你好傻啊
- You've been busy. - And you've been a complete idiot.
把克林特扯进来
Dragging in Clint.
把旺达从她不想离开的地方救出去
Rescuing Wanda from a place she doesn't even want to leave.
一个安全的地方  我在努力...
A safe place. I'm trying to keep....
我在努力阻止你分裂复仇者联盟
I'm trying to keep you from tearing the Avengers apart.
你签字时就已经分裂我们了
You did that when you signed.
好吧  行了
Alright, we're done.
交出巴恩斯  跟我们走
You're gonna turn Barnes over and you're gonna come with us,
马上照做  否则
now, because it's us
一支联合特别行动司令部的分队
or a squad of J-SOC guys...
会来抓你们  他们下手不会留情的
with no compunction about being impolite.
拜托了
Come on.
我们找到了
We found it.
昆式战斗机在北跑道的5号机库
The quinjet's in hanger five, north runway.
行动  朗
Alright, Lang.
各位  有什么东西
Hey, guys. Something...
那是什么情况
What-What the hell was that?
这是你的吧  美国队长
I believe this is yours, Captain America.
这可好  好了  停车场有俩
Oh, great. Alright, there's two on the parking deck.
其中一个是马克西莫夫  我去抓她
One of them is Maximoff, I'm gonna grab her.
罗德  你应付队长啊
Rhodey, you want to take Cap?
候机大厅有俩  威尔逊和巴恩斯
Got two in the terminal. Wilson and Barnes.
巴恩斯是我的
Barnes is mine!
斯塔克先生  我该做什么
Hey, Mr. Stark, what should I do?
不是说好了吗  别靠太近  用网缠住他们
What we discussed. Keep your distance. Web them up.
好的  收到
Okay, copy that!
让开  队长
Move, Captain.
我不会说第二遍
I won't ask a second time.
听着  我真的不想伤害你
Look, I really don't want to hurt you.
不必担心
I wouldn't stress about it.
-那是什么鬼  -这年头谁都有点花招
- What the hell was that? - Everyone's got a gimmick now.
你有金属臂  太牛逼了  哥们
You have a metal arm? That is awesome, dude!
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent!
对不住了  队长  虽然不致命
Sorry, Cap. This won't kill you
但还是会挺疼的
but it ain't gonna tickle either.
旺达  我觉得你伤了幻视的心
Wanda, I think you hurt Vision's feelings.
你把我关在房间里
You locked me in my room.
好吧  首先  这说法太夸张了
Okay. First, that's an exaggeration.
其次  我是为了保护你
Second, I did it to protect you.
-克林特  -伙计
- Hey, Clint. - Hey, man.
看来退休生活不适合你  高尔夫打烦了吗
Clearly retirement doesn't suit you. You got tired of shooting golf?
我玩18杆  杆杆进洞
Well, I played 18, shot 18.
就是射不偏
Just can't seem to miss.
-凡事总有第一次啊  -让你转头了
- First time for everything. - Made you look.
检测到多处挫伤
Multiple contusions detected.
嗯  我也检测到了
Yeah, I detected that too.
天啊
Oh, god.
伙计  这是你丢的吧
Hey, buddy, I think you lost this!
这翅膀是碳化纤维的
Those wings carbon fiber?
这玩意是你射出来的
Is this stuff coming out of you?
如果是  这刚柔度就不难理解了
That would explain the rigidity flexibility ratio.
我得说  真是牛逼
which, gotta say, that's awesome man.
不知道你参没参加过战斗
I don't know if you've been a fight before
但我们一般没这么多废话
but there's usually not this much talking.
好吧  不好意思  我的错
Alright, sorry, my bad.
两位  我也想继续和你们打
Guys, look. I'd love to keep this up
但我今天只有一项任务
but I've only got one job here today
我得给斯塔克先生留个好印象
and I gotta impress Mr. Stark,
真抱歉了  什么
so, I'm really sorry. What?
你就不能早点那么做吗
You couldn't have done that earlier?
讨厌
I hate you.
这可好
Great?
队长  接着
Cap, heads up!
朝这玩意扔
Throw it at this.
扔
Now!
不是吧
Oh, come on!
天呐  我以为是辆水车
Oh, man. I thought it was a water truck.
抱歉
Sorry.
好吧  我现在被惹毛了
Alright. Now, I'm pissed.
这是计划的一部分吗
Is this part of the plan?
我本来计划对他们客气些的  想加大火力吗
Well, my plan was go easy on them. You want to switch it up?
那是我们的飞机
There's our ride.
跟上
Come on!
罗杰斯队长
Captain Rogers.
我知道你相信自己是对的
I know you believe what you're doing is right.
但为了大局  你必须马上投降
But, for the collective good, you must surrender now.
怎么办  队长
What do we do, Cap?
我们战斗
We fight.
这下可好
This is gonna end well.
他们没打算停下来
They're not stopping.
我们也不会停
Neither are we.
-我们还是朋友吧  -要看你下手多狠了
- We're still friends, right? - Depends on how hard you hit me.
你放水了
You were pulling your punches.
-我没杀你父亲  -那你跑什么
- I didn't kill your father. - Then why did you run?
那玩意根本不符合物理定律啊
That thing does not obey the laws of physics at all.
孩子  这里有很多你不懂的事
Look kid. There's a lot going on here that you don't understand.
斯塔克先生说过你会这么说
Mr. Stark said you'd say that.
他还说要攻击你的腿
He also said to go for your legs.
克林特  能帮我甩掉他吗
Clint, can you get him off me?
-抓紧了吗  -抓紧了
- Buckled in? - Yeah. No, I'm good.
抓紧了  弓箭男  来吧
I'm good, arrow-guy. Let's go. Let's go!
斯塔克还跟你说别的了吗
Stark tell you anything else?
你错了  你觉得你没错
That you're wrong. You think you're right.
所以你很危险
That makes you dangerous.
他说得也没错
Guess he had a point.
你挺有勇气  你从哪来的
You got heart, kid. Where're you from?
皇后区
Queens.
我布鲁克林的
Brooklyn.
-星期五  -部分武器系统离线
- F.R.I.D.A.Y.? - We have some weapon systems offline.
什么
Hey, what?
估计得返厂维修了
Oh, you.. you're gonna have to take this into the shop.
-谁在说话  -你的良心
- Who's speaking? - It's your conscience.
我们最近都没怎么交流
We don't talk a lot these days.
-星期五 -启动灭火系统
- F.R.I.D.A.Y.? - Deploying fire suppression system.
天啊
Oh, boy.
我们得走了  那家伙现在都该到西伯利亚了
We got to go. That guy's probably in Siberia by now.
得把会飞的引开
We gotta draw out the fliers.
我应付幻视  你去飞机那儿
I'll take Vision. You get to the jet.
不  你们去上飞机  你俩都去
No, you get to the jet! Both of you!
我们其他人走不了了
The rest of us aren't getting out of here.
虽然我不想承认  如果我们想打赢
As much as I hate to admit it, if we're gonna win this one,
就得有些人输
some of us might have to lose it.
这不是真正重要的战斗  史蒂夫
This isn't the real fight, Steve.
好吧  山姆  什么计划
Alright, Sam, what's the plan?
我们得搞个大动静来转移注意力
We need a diversion, something big.
我有个大家伙  但坚持不了多久
I got something kind of big, but I can't hold it very long.
等我信号  拼命跑
On my signal, run like hell.
如果我把自己扯成了两半  也别回来救我
And if I tear myself in half, don't come back for me.
-他要把自己扯成两半了  -你没问题吗  斯科特
- He's gonna tear himself in half? - You sure about this, Scott?
我经常这样做  其实就那么一次
I do it all the time. I mean once...
在实验室里  然后我晕过去了
...in a lab. Then I passed out.
我最拽  我最拽  我最拽
I'm the boss. I'm the boss. I'm the boss.
我最拽
I'm the boss.
我勒个去
Holy shit!
那个小不点变大了  他变大了
Okay, tiny dude is big now. He's big now.
这大概就是信号了
I guess that's the signal.
厉害  小豆子
Way to go, tic-tac!
把我的罗德还我
Give me back my Rhodey.
我去接他
I got him!
好了  我们这边还有谁隐藏了什么惊人
Okay. Anybody on our side hiding any shocking,
了不起的能力想展现出来吗
and fantastic abilities they'd like to disclose,
我愿意接受建议
I'm open to suggestions.
你想抓他们  先过我这关
You want to get to them? You got to go through me.
我们还不认识彼此
We haven't met yet.
-我是克林特  -我不在乎
- I'm Clint. - I don't care.
下去
Get off.
有什么东西飞进我身体里了
Something just flew in me!
你不会停下的  是吗
You're not gonna stop?
你知道我不能
You know I can't.
我肯定要后悔的
I'm gonna regret this.
快走
Go.
各位  你们看过那部超老的电影吗
Hey, guys. You ever see that really old movie?
《帝国反击战》
Empire Strikes Back?
老天  托尼  这家伙多大
Jesus Tony, how old is this guy?
我不知道  我又没给他碳测年
I don't know, I didn't carbon date him.
反正挺小的
He's on the young side.
你知道那一段吗
You know that part?
就是他们在那个雪星球上  那个会走的机器
When they're on the snow planet? With the walking thingies?
这孩子的点子可能行得通
Maybe the kid's on to something.
往上飞  托尼  往上飞
High now, Tony. Go high.
好诶
Yes!
太牛逼了
That was awesome!
有人有橙片吗
Does anyone have any orange slices?
孩子  没事吧
Hey, kid, you alright?
-放开我  -友军
- Get off me! - Same side.
猜猜我是谁
Guess who?
是我
It's me.
-伙计  -嗯
- Hey, man. - Yeah.
-吓死人了  -是啊
- That was scary. - Yeah.
-你结束了  知道吗  -什么
- You're done. Alright? - What?
-你干得很好  待这儿吧  -我没事的
- You did a good job. Stay down.  - I'm good. I'm fine.
-待这儿吧  -不  我得把他抓回来
- Stay down. - No, it's good I gotta get him back!
回家去  否则我打给梅婶婶了
You're going home or I'll call Aunt May!
-伙计  -你收工了
- Dude. - You're done!
等等
Wait.
斯塔克先生  等等  我还能打  我...
Mr. Stark, wait! I'm not done, I'm not...
好吧  我不行了
Okay, I'm done. I'm done.
我说会帮你找到他  不是抓到他
I said that I'd help you find him, not catch him.
这是有区别的
There's a difference.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我也是
Me too.
就像我说的  灾难
It's as I said, catastrophe.
幻视  我后面有尾巴
Vision, I got a bandit on my six.
幻视  收到吗
Vision, do you copy?
打他的推进器  把他变成滑翔翼
Target his thruster, turn him into a glider.
罗德
Rhodey?
托尼  我失去动力了
Tony, I'm flying dead stick.
罗德
Rhodes!
读取体征
Read vitals.
检测到心跳  医疗急救已经上路
Heartbeat detected. Emergency medical is on it's way.
对不起
I'm sorry.
早上好  客房服务
Good morning. Room service.
早上好
Good morning.
我是201房间
This is room 201...
今天也要培根和黑咖啡吗
Bacon and black coffee again today?
你真了解我
You know me so well...
您好  早餐送来了
Hello? Your breakfast is here.
我可以进去吗
May I let myself in?
穆勒先生
Mr. Muller.
天呐
My God!
你的朋友会怎么样
What's gonna happen to your friends?
不管发生什么  我会去面对的
Whatever it is, I'll deal with it.
我不知道我是否值得你这样  史蒂夫
I don't know if I'm worth all this, Steve.
你那些年做的事
What you did all those years...
那不怪你
It wasn't you.
你没有选择
You didn't have a choice.
我知道
I know.
但终归是我做的
But I did it.
怎么会发生这种事
How did this happen?
我分心了
I became distracted.
我以为没那种可能呢
I didn't think that was possible.
我也以为
Neither did I.
医生说他L4到S1粉碎骨折
The doctor say he shattered L4 through S1.
脊髓高度撕裂
Extreme laceration of the spinal cord.
大概会造成一定瘫痪
Probably looking at some form of paralysis.
史蒂夫不会停下的
Steve's not gonna stop.
如果你也不让步  罗德的情况还算轻的了
If you don't either, Rhodey's gonna be the best case scenario.
你放走了他们  小娜
You let them go, Nat.
我们采取的方式不对
We played this wrong.
我们
We?
天呐  双面间谍一定很难改吧
Boy. It must be hard to shake the whole double agent thing, huh?
都深入骨髓了
It sticks in the DNA.
你就不能
And you incapable
放下你的自负  哪怕一刻吗
of letting go of your ego for one god damn second.
特查拉把你做的事告诉了罗斯
T'Challa told Ross what you did, so,
他们要来抓你了
they're coming for you.
需要小心的不是我
I'm not the one that needs to watch their back.
这是什么  星期五
What am I looking at, F.R.I.D.A.Y.?
柏林警方的优先上传信息
Priority upload from Berlin police.
启动直升机
Fire up the chopper.
巴恩斯被捕后
The Task Force called
特遣队立刻找了个精神病医生
for a psychiatrist as soon as Barnes was captured.
联合国一小时内就调来了
The UN dispatched Dr. Theo Broussard
日内瓦的西奥·布鲁萨尔医生
from Geneva within the hour.
此人去找到了他
He was met by this man.
你用面部识别查过他了吗
Did you run facial recognition yet?
你当我是什么人啊
What do I look like?
说不好  我一直脑补一个红发女子
I don't know, I've been picturing a redhead.
你想的肯定是别人
You must be thinking of someone else.
肯定是了
Must be.
假医生实为赫尔穆特·泽莫上校
The fake doctor's actually Colonel Helmut Zemo,
索科威亚情报部门的
Sokovian intelligence.
泽莫带领索科威亚的秘密刺杀小队回音蝎
Zemo ran Echo Scorpion, a Sokovian covert kill squad.
那真布鲁萨尔呢
So, what happened to the real Broussard?
他被发现死在了一家柏林酒店的房间里
He was found dead in a Berlin hotel room.
警方还在房间里找到了假发和面部假体
Where police also found a wig and facial prosthesis
用于模拟詹姆斯·布坎南·巴恩斯的特征
approximating the appearance of one James Buchanan Barnes.
该死
Son of a bitch.
-发给罗斯  -是  老板
- Get this to Ross. - Yes, Boss.
这里是孤岛监狱控制中心
This is Raft Prison control.
你可以降落了  斯塔克先生
You are clear for landing, Mr. Stark.
怎么样  拿到文件了吗
So? You got the files?
我们调整卫星
Let's reroute the satellites,
开始对这个泽莫进行面部识别扫描吧
start facial scanning for this Zemo guy.
在莱比锡制造了那么大个烂摊子
You seriously think I'm gonna listen to you
你真觉得我还会听你的吗
after that fiasco in Leipzig?
你没被关进这里的监狱就算你走运了
You're lucky you're not in one of these cells.
未来学家  先生们  未来学家来了
The futurist, gentlemen! The futurist is here!
他能看穿一切
He sees all!
他知道什么是为你好  不管你喜不喜欢
He knows what's best for you, whether your like it or not.
饶了我吧  巴顿
Give me a break, Barton.
我不知道他们会把你们关在这里  别这样
I had no idea they'd put you here, come on.
你知道他们会把我们关起来的  托尼
Yeah, well, you knew they'd put us somewhere, Tony.
是啊  但不是一个漂浮在海上的超级监狱
Yeah. But, not some super-max floating ocean pokey.
这地方是关疯子  关...
You know, this place is for maniacs. This is a place for...
罪犯
Criminals?
罪犯  托尼
Criminals, Tony.
你是想说这个
I think that's the word you're looking for.
是吧
Right?
这词以前可不会指我  或山姆  旺达
It ain't used to mean me, or Sam, or Wanda.
但我们还是被关进来了
But, here we are.
因为你犯法了
Cause you broke the law.
-是啊  -我可没逼你
- Yeah. - I didn't make you.
-啦啦啦  -你知法  还犯法
- Blah, blah, blah... - You read it, you broke it.
你是个大老爷们了  有妻有子
Alright, you're all grown-up. You got a wife and kids.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你选错队的时候怎么不去考虑他们
Why didn't you think about them before you choose the wrong side?
大家可得提防这家伙
You gotta watch your back with this guy.
搞不好他要背后坑你
There's a chances he's gonna break it.
汉克·皮姆一向说  斯塔克家人的人不能信
Hank Pym always said, you never can trust a Stark.
你是谁
Who are you?
拜托
Come on, man.
罗德怎么样了
How's Rhodes?
明天他要被送去哥大医院
Well, they're flying him to Columbia Medical tomorrow.
希望有帮助吧
So... Fingers cross.
你需要什么吗  他们给你饭吃了吗
What do you need? They feed you yet?
你现在是唱红脸的警察了
You're the good cop now?
我只是想知道史蒂夫去哪了
I'm just a guy who needs to know where Steve went.
那你得去找个唱白脸的来了
Well, you better go get a bad cop,
*辛普森案的关键证人警探  曝出录音带中自称曾对嫌疑人用刑逼供
你想要我开口  除非像马克·福尔曼
cause you gonna have to go Mark Fuhrman' on my ass
那样对我动大刑
to get information out of me.
我把他们监控的音频关掉了
Oh, I just knocked the 'A' out of their 'AV'.
我们有30秒时间
We got about 30 seconds
然后他们就会发现不是设备问题了
before they realize it's not their equipment.
你做了什么  把声音调出来
What did you do? Get it back up!
看这个
Just look.
这才是本该审问巴恩斯的人
Cause that is the fellow who was supposed to interrogate Barnes.
我显然是错了  山姆  我错了
Clearly, I made a mistake. Sam, I was wrong.
真是头一遭
That's a first.
队长现在不知要遭遇什么
Cap is definitely off the reservation
他会需要一切的帮助
but he's about to need all the help he can get.
我们不怎么熟  你不非得...
We don't know each other very well. You don't have to...
行了
It's alright.
我可以告诉你
Look, I'll tell you.
但你得作为朋友单独去
But you have to go alone and as a friend.
当然
Easy.
斯塔克  他说出罗杰斯的下落了吗
Stark, did he give you anything on Rogers?
没  他叫我下地狱
Nope. Told me to go to hell.
我还是回基地吧
I'm going back to the compound instead. But,
但你随时可以打给我
you can call me anytime.
我会让你待机  我喜欢看电话闪灯
I'll put you on hold, I like to watch the line blink.
罗曼诺夫
记得那次我们不得不搭冷藏车坐在后面冷库里
You remember that time we had to ride back from Rockaway Beach
回洛克威海滩吗
in the back of that freezer truck?
就是你拿我们坐地铁的钱买了热狗的那次吗
Was that the time you used our train money to buy hot dogs?
你为了替个红发女赢一只玩具熊花了3美元
You blew 3 bucks trying to win that stuffed bear for a redhead.
-她叫什么来着  -朵丽丝  你叫她小朵
- What was her name again? - Dolores. You called her Dot.
她现在肯定都一百岁了
She's got to be a hundred years old right now.
我们也是  伙计
So are we, pal.
他肯定也就到了几小时
He can't have been here more than a few hours.
那也足以唤醒他们了
Long enough to wake them up.
准备好了吗
Ready?
嗯
Yeah.
你戒心有点强啊
You seem a little defensive.
今天挺不容易的
It's been a long day.
稍息  士兵  我现在不是冲你来的
At ease, soldier. I'm not currently after you.
那你来做什么
Then why are you here?
或许你的说法没那么扯
Could be your story's not so crazy.
或许吧
Maybe.
罗斯不知道我来了  我也不希望他知道
Ross has no idea I'm here, I'd like to keep it that way.
否则  我还得逮捕自己
Otherwise, I got to arrest myself.
听上去要办很多公文呢
Well, that sounds like a lot of paper work.
-见到你很高兴  托尼  -我也是  队长
- It's good to see you, Tony. - You too, Cap.
*小说《谍网迷魂》美国政客之子被洗脑成为共产党杀手
洗脑战士  被你打败了
Manchurian Candidate, you're killing me.
我们休战了  你可以把枪放下了
There's a truce here, you can drop...
-我读取到热信号  -几个人
- I got heat signatures. - How many?
一个
Uh, one.
如果这算是安慰  他们是在睡梦中死去的
If it's any comfort, they died in their sleep.
你真以为我还想要更多你这样的人吗
Did you really think I wanted more of you?
搞什么
What the hell?
但我感激他们  他们把你引来了这里
I'm grateful to them though, they brought you here.
别费劲了  队长
Please, Captain.
苏联人将这个房间设计成
The Soviets built this chamber to withstand the launch blast of
可以抵挡UR100导弹
UR-100 rockets.
我打赌我有更强的火力
I'm betting I can beat that.
我相信你  斯塔克先生
Oh, I'm sure you could, Mr. Stark.
假以时日的话
Given time.
但那样你就无从知道你为何而来了
But then you'd never know why you came.
你在维也纳滥杀无辜
You killed innocent people in Vienna
就为了引我们来吗
just to bring us here?
一年多来  我满脑子都是你
I've thought about nothing else for over a year.
研究你  跟踪你
I studied you, I followed you.
但现在你站在这里  我才意识到
But now that you're standing here, I just realized...
你的蓝眼睛中还带点绿
There's a bit of green in the blue of your eyes.
能发现瑕疵真好
How nice to find a flaw.
你是索科威亚人
You're Sokovian.
就是为了这个吗
Is that what this is about?
索科威亚被你炸毁前早就无药可救了
Sokovia was a failed state long before you blew it to hell.
不
No.
这是为了我的一个承诺
I'm here because I made a promise.
你失去了什么人
You lost someone.
我失去了所有人
I lost everyone.
你也会的
And so will you.
1991年12月16日
被敌人颠覆的帝国还能东山再起
An empire toppled by its enemies can rise again.
但从内部坍塌的帝国
But one which crumbles from within...
就永远灭亡了
that's dead... forever.
我认得这条路
I know that road.
1991年12月16日
这是什么
What is this?
救救我妻子
Help my wife.
求你  救命
Please. Help.
巴恩斯中士
Sergeant Barnes.
霍华德
Howard.
Howard!
托尼  托尼
Tony. Tony.
你知道吗
Did you know?
我不知道是他
I didn't know it was him.
别骗我  罗杰斯  你知道吗
Don't bullshit me, Rogers! Did you know?
知道
Yes.
快走
Get outta here!
那不是他  托尼  九头蛇控制了他
It wasn't him, Tony. Hydra had control of his mind!
走开
Move!
那不是他
It wasn't him!
左靴喷气系统损坏
Left boot-jet failing.
飞行系统受损
Flight systems compromised.
该死
Ah, crap.
他不会罢休的  快走
He's not gonna stop. Go.
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
瞄准系统损坏  老板
Targeting system's knackered, boss.
我用肉眼瞄
I'm eyeballing it.
你记得他们吗
Do you even remember them?
我记得每一个人
I remember all of them.
这改变不了过去
This isn't gonna change what happened.
我不管
I don't care.
他杀了我妈
He killed my mom.
你真该看到他那张小脸  尽量赶回来  好吗
You should've seen his little face. Just try, okay?
我要睡了  我爱你
I'm going to bed. I love you.
我差点杀错了人
I almost kill the wrong man.
也不是什么无辜的人
Hardly an innocent one.
收件箱  空  信息已删除
你就是你想要的吗
This is all you wanted?
看他们自相残杀
To see them rip each other apart.
我父亲住在城外
My father lived outside the city.
我以为那儿会很安全
I thought we would be safe there.
我儿子很兴奋
My son was excited.
他可以透过车窗看到钢铁侠
He could see the Iron Man from the car window.
我告诉我妻子  "不用担心
And I told my wife, "Don't worry."
他们在城里打仗
"They're fighting in the city.
我们离得远呢  不会有事"
We are miles from harm."
等灰烬散尽
When the dust cleared,
尖叫声停止
and the screaming stopped.
我花了两天才找到他们的尸体
It took me two days until I found their bodies.
我父亲
My father...
依然抱着我的妻儿
still holding my wife and son in his arms.
而复仇者联盟
And the Avengers...
他们就那么回家了
they went home.
我知道自己杀不了他们
I knew I couldn't kill them.
比我更强大的人都试过了
More powerful men than me have tried.
但如果我能让他们自相残杀呢
But, if I could get them to kill each other?
你父亲的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your father.
他似乎是个好人
He seemed a good man.
有个孝子
With a dutiful son.
复仇已经吞噬了你
Vengeance has consumed you.
也吞噬了他们
It's consuming them.
我不会让自己也被吞噬
I am done letting it consume me.
正义很快就会到来
Justice will come soon enough.
和死人说去吧
Tell that to the dead.
活人还要找你呢
The living are not done with you yet.
你无法靠肉搏打败他
You can't beat him hand to hand.
分析他的攻击模式
Analyse his fight pattern.
扫描中
Scanning!
对抗策略就绪
Countermeasures ready.
我们好好揍他一顿
Let's kick his ass.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
我原本也是
So was I.
不要起来  最后警告
Stay down. Final warning.
我可以和你耗一整天
I could do this all day.
那块盾牌不属于你
That shield doesn't belong to you.
你配不上它  那是我父亲制造的
You don't deserve it! My father made that shield!
早上八点  晚上五点吃饭
Meals at eight and five.
每天可以去两次厕所
Toilet privileges, twice a day.
大声说话  电你
Raise your voice, zap.
碰玻璃  电你
Touch the glass, zap.
敢做出格的事  我会收拾你
You step out of line, you deal with me.
拜托你试试看吧
Please, step out of line.
感觉怎么样
So, how does it feel?
花了那么多时间  费了那么多事
Spend all that time, all that effort.
结果
Then...
失败得
...to see it fail,
一塌糊涂
so spectacularly.
有吗
Did it?
-这只是首次测试  -嗯
- It's just the first pass. - Yeah.
给我反馈  想到什么都行
Give me some feedback. Anything you think of.
减震  横向移动
Shock absorption. Lateral movement.
杯架
Cup holder?
或许该考虑在下面按空调
You may wanna think about some AC down in...
好了  我拉你
Let's go. I'll give you a hand.
不不  别帮我  别帮我
No, no, don't. Don't help. Don't help me.
138次  138次战斗任务
138. 138 combat missions.
我飞过138次战斗任务  托尼
That's how many I've flown, Tony.
每次都可能有去无回  但我还是去了
Every one of them could've been my last, but I flew them.
因为那是必须打的仗
Cause the fight needed to be fought.
《协议》的事也是一样
It's the same with these Accords.
我签字是因为那是正确的做法
I signed because it was the right thing to do.
这事的确太糟心了
And yeah, this sucks. This is, uh...
真是不走运
This is a bad beat.
但这没改变我的想法
But it hasn't change my mind.
我觉得没有
I don't think?
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You okay? - Oh, yeah.
你是托尼·"屎塔克"吗
Are you Tony "Stank"?
是的  他就是托尼·"屎塔克"  你来对地方了
Yes, this is-this is Tony "Stank"! You're in the right place.
多谢了
Thank you for that!
-这梗我要用一辈子  -天呐
- Never dropping that, by the way. - Oh, my god.
一人桌  "屎塔克"先生  坐在厕所边吧
Table for one, Mr. "Stank". Please, by the bathroom.
托尼
Tony.
我很高兴你回到了基地
I'm glad you're back at the compound.
我不希望你一个人在豪宅里晃
I don't like the idea of you rattling around a mansion by yourself.
我们都需要家人
We all need family.
复仇者联盟属于你  或许多于属于我
The Avengers are yours, maybe more so than mine.
我从18岁开始就是一个人
I've been on my own since I was 18.
我从未真正融入哪里  哪怕是在军队
I never really fit in anywhere, even in the army.
我想我信任  人  个体
My faith's in... people, I guess. Individuals.
很高兴  大部分时候
And, I'm happy to say that for the most part,
他们没让我失望
they haven't let me down.
所以我也不能辜负他们
Which is why I can't let them down either.
锁可以换  但或许不该换
Locks can be replaced, but, maybe they shouldn't.
我知道我伤了你  托尼
I know I hurt you, Tony.
我大概是觉得
I guessed I thought
不告诉你你父母的事  是照顾你的感情
by not telling you about your parents, I was sparing you. But...
但我现在明白  我只是在照顾自己
I can see now that I was really sparing myself.
对不起
And I'm sorry.
希望你有天能理解
Hopefully one day you can understand.
我也希望我们能在《协议》的事上达成一致
I wish we agree on the Accords,
真的
I really do.
我知道你只是在做你相信的事
I know you're doing what you believe in.
而我们也都只能做到这点  我们也该这么做
And that's all any of us can do. That's all any of us should.
国务卿罗斯的优先来电
Priority call from Secretary Ross.
孤岛监狱遭人劫狱
There's been a breach at the Raft Prison.
嗯  接过来
Yeah, put him through.
-托尼  我们有麻烦了  -请待机
- Tony, we have a problem. - Ah, please hold.
不  别
No. Don't...
所以  不管怎样
So, no matter what.
我保证
I promise you,
如果你需要我们
if you need us,
如果你需要我
if you need me,
我会去的
I'll be there.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
我不能信任自己的大脑
I can't trust my own mind.
直到他们想到办法把洗脑的东西清理掉
So, until they figure out how to get this stuff out of my head
我想继续沉睡是最好的选择
I think going back under is the best thing,
对所有人都好
... for everybody.
谢谢你帮忙
Thank you for this.
你的朋友和我父亲
Your friend and my father,
他们都是受害者
they were both victims.
如果我能帮其中一个找到安宁
If I can help one of them find peace.
如果他们知道他在这儿
You know, if they find out he's here,
就会来抓他
they'll come for him.
让他们试试吧
Let them try.
是谁啊  是谁打了你
So. Who was it? Who hit you?
就是有个人
Some guy.
痒死了  天呐
So itchy, man. God.
-有个人叫什么  -史蒂夫
- What's some guy's name? - Uh, Steve.
史蒂夫
Steve?
-哎呦  -12C那个吗
- Yikes. - From 12C?
龅牙那个
With the overbite?
不不不  你不认识他  他布鲁克林的
No, no, no. You don't know him, he's from Brooklyn.
好吧
Well.
希望你也回敬他了几下
Hope you got a few good licks in.
当然  我回敬了他好几下呢
Yeah, I got quite a few in actually.
好
Okay.
他朋友块头可大了  可大可大了
His friend was huge. Like huge.
这样好多了  谢谢
That's way better. Thank you.
好吧  小硬汉
Okay, tough guy.
爱你  梅  能带下门吗
Love you, May. Hey, can you shut the door?
蜘蛛侠将回归